mashreqbank.com 2012-11-19

# Privacy Policy -Mashreq Bank

As your financial services partner, Mashreq understands that your trust in us is our most important asset. In order to preserve that trust, we want you to clearly understand what personal information we collect about you and how we use it. As a Mashreq customer, you have the opportunity to opt out from marketing communication lists or to specify your preferred channel of communication to receive notification of our latest offers and promotions. 

To give you effective and convenient access to a broad range of financial products and services, we use technology to manage and maintain customer information.  We understand the need to safeguard sensitive information that you have entrusted to us. Therefore, we have put together a Privacy Policy that respects and addresses your needs. It also explains what types of information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it.

## Collecting Customer Information

Mashreqbank collects only relevant information about you that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you that is "non-public." Non-public personal information is information about you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service to you. The information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:-

### Application Information

We retain personal information from any application you submit for deposit accounts, Electronic Fund Transfers (EFT) services, loans or other Bank services. This includes but is not limited to information such as name, postal and e-mail address, phone numbers, employment and financial status, and credit history.

### Your Transactions

We retain the transaction information any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, transactions through Internet Banking, over the phone or at a branch. The transaction information includes your account number, date, amount, location of the transaction and any other pertinent information.

### Online

We obtain information online when you visit our website www.mashreqbank.com. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, Internet banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail.

## Sharing Information with Our Bank Affiliates

In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliates ( **[click here](http://about-us/affiliates/affiliates.asp)** for a list of affiliates). We may share personal information (such as name, address and account number) and account information (such as type of accounts, account balances and transaction history) with our affiliates so that they can serve you more efficiently. Our affiliates maintain the same privacy standards as the Bank.

## Sharing Information with Third-Party Service Providers

In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we may need to share information with our service providers, including data processing companies, cheque, ATM, and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, insurance companies, collection agencies, credit reporting agencies and financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the customer information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information with third-party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

  * Personal information (name, address and account number)
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances and transaction history)
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations and type of transaction)

We do not share your account numbers with independent third-party marketers offering their own products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of our affiliates or other financial service providers, we control the customer information used in connection with these offers.

## Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted

We may share your customer information in response to a lawful request issued by -

  * a court
  * a government agency
  * a regulatory authority
  * or as permitted by law 

We may also share your information in response to a request made by a merchant or business necessary to effect, administer or enforce a transaction that you had requested or authorized in connection with the servicing or processing of a financial product or service, or to maintain or service your account with us.   

## Protecting Information 

### Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards

We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that customer information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees and contractors are only permitted access to customer information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide services to you. Our employees and contractors have access to such customer information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees and contractors are required to respect customer privacy. No one except our employees and contractors has access to the Bank’s computer system and records storage. The Bank has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide to us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your customer information as we employ new technology in the future.

### Information Integrity Measures

Mashreq works hard to ensure that the customer information we maintain is complete and accurate. We have procedures and processes for updating our customer information as well as removing old, outdated information. We have measures in place to protect the integrity of customer information such as maintaining back-up copies of account data in the event of power outages or other business interruptions. We use computer virus detection and eradication software and employ other technical means (known as "firewalls") to protect against unauthorized computer entry into systems containing customer information.   

### Online Privacy Protection

From our website (<http://www.mashreqbank.com/> ), you may apply for accounts and services, and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide to us online, we use multiple levels of security. When you log onto our website, you will only be able to successfully access it if your computer has an up-to-date browser (i.e., Internet Explorer, FireFox, Mozilla, Netscape, etc) that operates at a high level of data encryption (128 bit). This ensures that there is an adequate level of security for online activity. Generally, e-mail communication over the Internet cannot be assumed to be secure. If we ask you to e-mail us information other than your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, we will always use the secure encrypted e-mail facility available on mashreqonline when you sign on to view your accounts. Our firewalls protect Mashreqbank’s systems, only permitting access to authorized users. This gives you comfort that you are indeed connected to a genuine Mashreqbank server. Our server security standards and policies are certified by Thawte, one of the world’s most prominent technology security organizations (click here for more details). Only registered users will have an access to mashreqonline by using their password. Additional security measures are in place to effect funds transfer requests through mashreqonline.

### Cookies

We do not use cookies with visitors to our general website. However, we do use cookies with customers who sign on to our online banking services, to make access more pleasant and convenient. The cookie generated once you sign on to our online banking service expires as soon as you log out or at a predefined time, and to protect your privacy we do not store any sensitive information such as customer information in the cookie.  To find out more information about cookies, please visit <http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.mspx>

## Keeping Up-To-Date With Our Privacy Policy

In order to keep our customers up-to-date with our Privacy Policy, we will send you our Privacy Policy annually (by post or email), as long as you maintain an ongoing relationship with us. We may amend this Policy at any time, and we will inform you of changes as required by law. You can always review our current Policy on our website at: [www.mashreqbank.com](http://www.mashreqbank.com/).

## Privacy Policy Inquiries

If you have any questions about our privacy practices write to us at Mashreqbank, Attn: Customer Care Center, P.O. Box 1250, Dubai, UAE.

## Making Sure Information is Accurate

Keeping your account information accurate and up-to-date is very important. If you ever find that your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please sign onto mashreqonline to update your information or contact our Customer Care Center at +971 4 424 4444 and our agents will promptly update or correct any erroneous information.

## Marketing preference – your choice

As a Mashreqbank customer, we let you select your preferred channel of communication for marketing updates sent to you on a periodic basis. Your choices include the following:

  1. Receive marketing communications through any channel (Snail mail, Email, SMS, Tele calling)
  2. Receive marketing communications through SMS and email only
  3. Receive marketing communications through SMS only
  4. Receive marketing communications through email only
  5. Communicate only through Relationship Manager (Applicable to Mashreq Gold customers only)
  6. Opt out of marketing communications*

*Customers may still receive marketing information with account statements posted to them.  The opt out does not affect this. 

If you have opted for marketing via SMS banking, as part of our Customer Contact Rule we shall restrict the time for dispatch of messages between 8 am to 7 pm.
